VENKATA YOGA GOWRI KRISHNAN

TORONTO

| (437) 981-3814 | gowrikarthick20@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/venkata-yoga-gowrikrishnan23071995/ |

A Passionate web developer with three years of experience in front end development currently updating my skills to excel my career as a developer. Starting my career as a developer-trainee I learnt web technologies and implemented them in my projects. Seeking to leverage acquired technical knowledge and professional expertise to grow as a developer. A dedicated worker aiming to help achieve company goals and take on more responsibility as quickly as possible.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS:

- Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Responsive Development, SAPUI5.
- **Frameworks**: Bootstrap, React JS.
- **Database**: MYSOL.
- **IDE**: Visual studio code, Eclipse, Notepad++.
- Version Control system: Git, GitHub.
- Tracking tools: JIRA, Confluence.
- Other tools: Microsoft Teams.
- SDLC methodologies: Agile, Waterfall.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

1.FRONT-END-DEVELOPER, TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES

[DEC 2018- JAN 2020]

KOCHI, INDIA.

PROJECT DETAILS: <u>BAYER</u>: A website for the client Bayer to publish their enterprise in global market. The scope of the project was to establish their core competencies in the life science field of healthcare and agriculture.

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES:

TECH SUMMARY: CSS3, SASS, jQuery, Bootstrap, Media query, JIRA.

- Gathered and defined customer requirements to develop clear specifications for project plans.
- Worked with CSS3, media queries and Bootstrap to create responsive web design.
- Created maintainable styling sheets by using variables and mixings with SASS.
- Created animation for the images present in the website.
- Extensively used jQuery in implementing various GUI components in application.
- Updated tasks and bug fixes using JIRA.
- Worked closely with QA team in resolving defects.
- Provided tech support for the application post production.

KOCHI, INDIA

PROJECT DETAILS: <u>ALGOMA-ESSAR STEELS</u>: An Internal website for the employees to post bulk orders received, 3 levels of authority approval, Production status and delivery.

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Gathered and defined customer requirements to develop clear specifications for project plans.
- Created UI components using SAPUI5 modules.
- Worked with CSS3, media queries and Bootstrap to create responsive web design.
- Implemented custom modules and functionalities using JavaScript.
- Updated tasks and bug fixes using JIRA.
- Worked closely with QA team in resolving defects.

TECH SUMMARY: SAPUI5, CSS3, JAVASCRIPT, JIRA.

3.DEVELOPER-INTERN, TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES

[MARCH 2017- JULY2017]

CHENNAI, INDIA.

PROJECT DETAILS: NGO WEBPAGE: A webpage designed for an event in non-profit organization. This page contains different events on a date and different food items offered on the eve of the festival and all the information for the visitors including the event location, schedule of the cultural activities and food menu.

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Created the web page using HTML5 and Bootstrap Carousel.
- Worked with CSS layout, CSS Positioning, CSS text, Pseudo classes and pseudo elements.
- Revised, modularized and updated old code bases to modern development standards.
- Worked with CSS and Bootstrap to create responsive web design for multiple components.

TECH SUMMARY: HTML5, CSS3, BOOTSTRAP.

EDUCATION:

Bachelor of engineering in Electronics and communication, Anna university

[Jun2012- May2016]

TRICHY, INDIA (G.P.A-8.49)

CERTIFICATIONS:

Internal TCS certification on HTML5 and CSS3.